papyrusonline.com 2019-09-22

# Privacy & Security

_Updated and effective as of April 16th, 2019_

**Thank you for visiting the Papyrus online store.** Papyrus takes your privacy seriously and is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Because we do gather certain types of information from visitors to our website, we have developed a privacy policy to help our visitors understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of information. This policy only applies to visitors accessing our website (papyrusonline.com) from the United States and Canada, and does not apply to data that may be collected offline or in our stores. By visiting our website you are accepting the practices described in this policy. If you do not agree with these terms, do not use or visit the website. 

Please refer here for the SRG Retail Store Privacy Policy. 

##### Guiding Principles

  * Papyrus collects information online to provide our visitors with a more relevant experience on our web site and to effect transactions through our online store.
  * Papyrus takes reasonable physical, electronic and managerial measures to safeguard and secure any information you provide to us.
  * Papyrus honors its customers' requests to not receive future marketing communications from Papyrus.

##### Information Collected

Generally, you may visit the Papyrus website without revealing personal information about yourself. When you visit the Papyrus website, we (or a third-party service we authorize) assign an anonymous persistent identifier to facilitate your visit. We or our authorized third-party service providers may also collect anonymous information when you visit the Papyrus website, including the type of device used to browse our website, the operating system, browser type or IP address, and behavioral usage data. This information enables us to improve our website, tailor our advertising for better relevance, and helps us discover any issues people may have in using our website.

During the process of making an online purchase, we ask for your name, email address, phone number, mailing address and your credit card information or other payment information to complete your order. When you make an online purchase, you can choose to register on our website, in which case and we may use this information to further assist your ordering experience by reminding you of products that were left in your shopping bag or requesting feedback on purchased items. You do not have to register on our website to complete a purchase. In addition, you may be able to submit information such as your name and/or e-mail address through various forms, including, contact forms and e-mail list sign-ups, which we will use to contact you.

##### Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

Papyrus may use personally identifiable information to provide information and services to you and to allow Papyrus to (i) respond to questions and comments; (ii) analyze and monitor your use of the website and the service; (iii) promote, operate and support Papyrus products and services, including to send you newsletters and periodic promotional materials; (iv) develop a knowledge base regarding its users; (v) process orders; (vi) improve the services and website; (vii) use for internal business purposes; and (viii) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your personal information.

Papyrus may share relevant personal information that we have collected with third-party vendors in order for them to carry out work on our behalf, such as deploying marketing emails, payment processing or serving targeted advertisements. Third-party vendors are required to hold your personal information in confidentiality, although aggregated or anonymized data may be utilized by third-party vendors for their own usage with our consent. If you do not want us to share your personal information with any third parties, please visit our [Email Unsubscribe](https://www.papyrusonline.com/email-unsubscribe-ppy) page and submit your email address there or select the "opt out" box on our online forms, but please understand that such a request will likely limit your ability to take advantage of all of the features and services we offer on the Papyrus website.

If you direct any of your information, including personally identifiable information, to be shared with third parties, such as social media sites, third-party mobile applications, and similar services, Papyrus will have no control over these third-party uses of your information.

Papyrus may disclose specific personal information based on a good-faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to comply with or conform to the law (subpoenas, warrants) or that such disclosure is necessary to protect the users of the website or the public or to otherwise enforce our rights.

Further, in the event Papyrus sells or transfers a particular portion of its business assets, consumer information may be one of the business assets transferred as part of the transaction. If substantially all of the assets of Papyrus are acquired, consumer information may be transferred as part of the acquisition.

##### Use of Cookies & Similar Technologies

Papyrus and third-party vendors may use a browser feature known as a "cookie." Cookies are small text files placed on your computer that allow Papyrus to enhance the functionality of an online store by, among other things, saving the contents of your shopping cart or recognizing your log-in status between browsing sessions. Cookies and similar technologies may also be used by Papyrus and authorized third-party vendors, including Google, to collect non-personally identifiable information so that we may tailor our advertising or enhance your shopping experience according to your interests. Our site may also use the following services to facilitate interest-based advertising: Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, and other integrated Google services, each of which uses tracking technologies to understand and improve online advertising. We do not control those tracking technologies and we are not responsible for them. However, you understand that when you use our website you may potentially encounter third-party tracking technologies and accept that our statements under this Privacy Policy do not apply to the tracking technologies or practices of such third parties. Papyrus may also use beacons, pixel tags or similar technologies from authorized third-party services to collect anonymous browsing behavior for the purpose of analyzing visitor activity and using this data to improve our visitors' website experiences. Cookies are not used to store sensitive personal information.

The "Help" feature on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-on's settings or visiting the Web site of its manufacturer. Because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of Papyrus' features, we recommend that you leave them turned on.

If you would prefer not to have our partners use this data to deliver relevant advertising on other websites, the Network Advertising Initiative provides an opt-out tool for the purpose of opting out of Internet-based advertising by its participating member companies. It is located at the following link: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>. If you delete your cookies, use a different web browser, or use a different computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choice.

##### Use of Technology to Communicate with Mobile Devices

We use Bluetooth (BLE) Beacons, Wi-Fi, and similar technologies within some of our locations that may communicate with your (mobile) device and identify its location if the device has Bluetooth and/or Wi-Fi enabled and is properly configured. As a result, we may collect your Wi-Fi and/or Bluetooth MAC Address and send BLE signals to your device. We do not collect any personal information when we do so. To opt out of BLE Beacons and/or the collection of your MAC address, turn off your device Bluetooth and Wi-Fi capabilities.

##### Do Not Track Signals

Some web browsers allow you to request that websites and advertisers not track you by turning on the "Do Not Track" preference in the web browser settings. In the interest of serving our visitors, we have not set up our website to accommodate the Do Not Track signal as certain functions on most modern websites require some level of tracking ability to be useful to visitors.

##### Editing Your Personal Information

You can visit papyrusonline.com without telling us who you are or providing us with any personal information. However, during the course of browsing and shopping on the Papyrus website it is possible for you to create a customer account that will allow you to save addresses, item customizations, shopping cart contents, your order history and other personal information that would help make your shopping experience easier. We store this information until a request is submitted to either delete or edit. If you ever need to edit your saved personal information, you may log into your customer account and edit your personal information at your own convenience. If you require assistance editing or deleting your personal information, you may contact Customer Service through our Contact Form. If so, we will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in our then active databases as soon as reasonably practicable (but we may retain prior information as business records).

##### How We Communicate with You

Papyrus may send communications to you on the basis of the information you provide to us through email or postal mail. You may always specifically request not to be contacted (see Opt-Out Procedures below).

##### Opt-Out Procedures

You may always opt-out of receiving future marketing communications from Papyrus by (a) clicking the "Unsubscribe" link at the bottom of the email message, (b) visiting our Email Preferences page and unsubscribing from there, or (c) making a request through Customer Service. It may take several weeks to have your name removed from our files depending on how you make your request. Your request not to receive marketing communications from us will not preclude us from contacting you regarding a question we have about your purchase or sending you transactional messages.

The Network Advertising Initiative provides an opt-out tool for the purpose of opting out of Internet-based advertising by its participating member companies. It is located at the following link: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>. If you delete your cookies, use a different web browser, or use a different computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choice.

##### Protect Children Accessing this Web Site

Papyrusonline.com is a general audience website and is not intended for children under the age of 13, and we will not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Children under the age of 13 should obtain parental consent before accessing this website.

##### Links to Third-Party Sites

The Papyrus website may contain links to other websites, however please be aware that our Privacy Policy does not apply to websites other than papyrusonline.com. Papyrus is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of other websites. To help ensure your privacy, Papyrus recommends that you review the privacy policy of any website you visit.

##### Passwords

The personal data record created through your registration with this website can only be accessed with the unique password associated with that record. To protect the integrity of the information contained in this record you should not disclose or otherwise reveal your password to third parties.

##### Transfer of Information to the United States

Our website is operated in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect, including personal information, will be transferred to, and processed, stored and used in the United States. The data protection laws in the United States may differ from those of the country in which you are located, and your personal information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States according to laws of the United States. By using the website or providing us with any information, you consent to the transfer to, and processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information, including personal information, in the United States as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

##### Security

While we strive to do our part to protect your personal information, due to the nature of the Internet, the privacy and security of every transmission over the Internet cannot be guaranteed.

We use a secure server utilizing the SSL security to encrypt your personal information. When accessing our customer log-in, account management or checkout pages, your browser should indicate that you have entered our secure browsing zone, where all traffic to and from papyrusonline.com is encrypted. Each web browser offers a different security indicator, although most use the "lock" icon next to the web address—please refer to your browser's help section to learn more. If you do not see any secure browsing indicators, please call our customer service number at 1-707-399-3775 to complete your transaction.

Please note as well that email is not encrypted and is not considered to be a secure means of transmitting sensitive personal information.

##### Terms of Use

Any dispute or claim relating in any way to your use of this website, including this privacy policy, will be resolved by binding arbitration, rather than in court. You are waiving your right to sue in court for such disputes. There is no judge or jury in arbitration, and court review of an arbitration award is limited. The Federal Arbitration Act and federal arbitration law apply to this agreement.

##### Pricing

Despite our best efforts, a small number of the items on our website may be mispriced. If the correct price of an item sold by by us is higher than our stated price, we will, at our discretion, either contact you for instructions before shipping or cancel your order and notify you of such cancellation.

##### Mobile Messaging Terms & Conditions

###### What is PAPYRUS Mobile Messaging?

PAPYRUS Mobile Messaging is a program where we use SMS text messages to notify customers of special offers, sales and events. We send up to 10 times a month. No purchase is necessary for subscription.

###### How do I sign up for PAPYRUS Mobile Messaging?

Join PAPYRUS Mobile Messaging by texting XOXO to the short code 86156. You will receive up to 10 messages a month. PAPYRUS Mobile Messaging is not spam. By texting XOXO to 86156, you consent to receive marketing text messages from PAPYRUS. You are not obligated to purchase any goods or services in order to receive messages. Messages will be sent to the mobile number used at opt-in. We may send text messages using an automatic telephone dialing system. You must notify PAPYRUS if your number is changed or deactivated by contacting our customer service team at (707) 399-3775. You will receive a confirmation text message as part of registration and may opt out by replying STOP to any message.

You also affirm that you are at least 13 years of age or older, are authorized to agree to receive mobile contacts on this phone number and are responsible for any mobile message or data charges incurred. If you are between 13 and 17 years old, you are confirming parental consent to enroll your number in PAPYRUS Mobile Message except where restricted by state law.

###### Is it free?

Although PAPYRUS Mobile Messaging is complimentary, messages and data rates may apply. Depending on your texting plan, you may be charged by your carrier. By providing your consent to participate in PAPYRUS Mobile Messaging, you approve any such charges from your mobile carrier. Charges for text messages may appear on your mobile phone bill or be deducted from your prepaid balance.

###### What if I don't want to receive any more promotional/alert messages?

To STOP receiving messages from PAPYRUS, simply text "STOP" to the short code 86156. After doing so you will no longer receive any PAPYRUS messages. We will take you off our messaging list within 24 hours.

###### What if I want back in?

You can start receiving PAPYRUS again by following the steps outlined above in the section: "How do I sign up for PAPYRUS Mobile Messaging?"

###### What if I want more info?

To request more info simply text "HELP" to the short code 86156.

###### Commands

**STOP:** At any time, you can text "STOP" to the short code 86156. This will prevent you from receiving any future PAPYRUS messages. It may take us up to 24 hours to implement your request.

**HELP:** At any time, you can text "HELP" to the short code 86156. Texting "HELP" will return the following message: PAPYRUS: For more info on PAPYRUS, contact https://www.papyrusonline.com/customer-service, or call (707) 399-3775. Txt STOP to stop. Msg&data rates may apply.

Customer Service Phone #: (707) 399-3775

###### Who are the Participating Carriers?

Participating carriers include AT&T, T-Mobile®, Verizon Wireless, Sprint, Boost, U.S. Cellular, Cellular One, MetroPCS, ACS/Alaska, Bluegrass Cellular, Cellular One of East Central Illinois, Centennial Wireless, Cox Communications, EKN/Appalachian Wireless, GCI, Google Voice, Illinois Valley Cellular, Immix/Keystone Wireless, Inland Cellular, Nex-Tech Wireless, Rural Cellular Corporation, Thumb Cellular, United Wireless, West Central (WCC), Cellcom, Cellsouth, Cricket, and Virgin Mobile.

###### Additional Information

T-Mobile® and other mobile carriers are not liable for delayed or undelivered messages. By subscribing to PAPYRUS Mobile Messaging, you agree to receive autodialed marketing messages and text messages at a telephone number that is unambiguously designated by the user. Terms & Conditions are subject to change. PAPYRUS reserves the right to terminate PAPYRUS Mobile Messaging service at any time without notice. The information in any message may be subject to certain time lags and or delays. You are responsible for managing the types of SMS texts you receive.

###### What is your Privacy Policy?

You can view our Privacy Policy by visiting the link below:  
https://www.papyrusonline.com/customer-services/privacy-security

##### Your California Privacy Rights

Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice describing what categories of personal information we share with third parties or corporate affiliates for those third parties or corporate affiliates' direct marketing purposes. That notice will identify the categories of information shared and will include a list of the third parties and affiliates with which it was shared, along with their names and addresses. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to [customerservice[at]papyrusonline.com](https://www.papyrusonline.com/customer-service). In your request, please specify that you want a "Your California Privacy Rights Notice". Please allow at least 30 days for a response.

##### Policy Changes

We reserve the right to change, modify, or amend this policy at any time. If amended, the effective date of the policy amendment will always be posted at the beginning of this policy. The new policy will replace any prior policies to the extent that there are any inconsistencies. Use of this website after modification, implies that you consent to the policy as amended. To the extent any provision of this Privacy Policy is found by a competent tribunal to be invalid or unenforceable, such provision shall be severed to the extent necessary for the remainder to be valid and enforceable.
